Okay, so hello everyone in this video, we are going to just check up with our logout functionality.
Okay.
So up till now, we have made this login page as well as sign up page, right?
So in the sign up page, we have made the account for the user and in the login page,
we are just accessing like we are trying to login with those credentials that we have set up.
But since we have implemented both functions and in the login,
it should redirect to some page right in some home page when we are going to log in, right?
So in that case, what we are going to actually do is let's go to the app.jsx
and I'm going to explain you on the way what we are actually going to do.
So on the top of it, first import the route.
So actually we are going to route it like route the request, whatever like after the login,
we are going to display some page right.
So for that case only, we are going to use this route comma routes from react out of them.
So we are going to navigate to the home page as soon as we hit the login.
So now after this, oh, actually we have already done this and also no issues.
So as you can see that route path equal to slash that means home page and element equal to home page.
So it is going to redirect to the home page.
So one conditions which we can actually add is like suppose we need to get that logged user right.
So on that condition, we are going to render the home page.
So for that reason what I'm actually going to do is const logged user.
So logged user, I'm going to get that user from the author store.
Okay.
So from the author store and after this, what I'm actually going to do is we are going to add some conditions here.
So like element equals to home page right.
So here we can do things like like suppose the logged in user is there.
Okay.
In that case, we are going to just navigate to the home page.
Otherwise we are going to navigate to the.
So navigate navigate to equals to we are going to go to the login page.
Okay. So that would be one thing and for the sign of page, similarly we are going to do the same thing.
Like suppose if the logged in user, like logged user is not present in that case, we are going to go to the sign of page.
Otherwise we are going to navigate to the home page.
So to the home page.
Okay.
So this would be for the sign of page.
Similarly for the login page, we are going to do the same thing.
Like if the logged user is not present, then in that case, we are going to go to the log login page.
And otherwise what we are going to do is we are going to the home page.
So navigate to equals to slash.
And we'll be visiting like this.
So now after this profile, okay, is the logged user present is the logged user present.
If it is present, then that case we are going to navigate to the profile page.
Otherwise we are going to navigate to the.
Navigate to equals to.
I guess this logic would be fine.
Okay.
So this is what we are actually going to do.
And after this, let's set up the logic for the logged out user.
Okay.
So we are going to go to the author store.js.
So let's verify this one first.
Okay.
So route path equal to slash.
That means in the home page is the logged in user present.
Yeah.
If the logged in user is present in that case, we are going to go to the navigate.
We are going to the home page.
Otherwise we are going to navigate to the login screen.
Okay.
Another case, it would be like if the logged user is not present.
In that case, we are going to go to the sign of page.
Otherwise, we are going to navigate to the home page.
Okay.
Similarly, for the logged in user, if it's not present in the slash login page.
Then that case, we are going to the login page.
Otherwise, we are going to navigate to the home page.
Okay.
That's fine.
Now, after this, let's go to the.
Author store.js.
Okay.
So there would be one fine.
So now we are going to write the logic for the log out.
So for that case, let's go to the comma.
Async.
And now after this, we are going to use the callback function.
And let's use the try and catch block.
Try and catch.
Try and catch block.
And after this, const.js equals to.
Oh wait.
Axios instance.
So this would be, I think, yeah, this would be a get request.
Right.
So get request.
And slash.
Last log out.
Okay.
After this one, set the.
Log the user to null.
Since we are.
Moving out from the website, we are logging out.
And display the success misses using the to start success that.
Log.
Log out successful log out success.
Cool.
Okay.
Otherwise, we can catch the error in the catch block.
And.
And this one.
We are going to use this toast dot error.
And in this error, we are going to say that log in failed.
Okay.
Log out fail actually.
Log out failed.
And for this error part, console dot log error.
It's not going to throw any kind of error.
Right.
So why it's used here.
Arise is declared.
The value is never used.
Why.
Okay.
No issues.
We are actually not using this right now.
Okay.
So.
That would be fine.
Now let's go to the neighbor.
So neighbor dot jsex.
So in the neighbor dot jsex, what we actually can do.
Let me think.
Yeah.
We have to do the log out right.
So in that case, we are.
We'll get some button here.
So log out button.
So we have to add that like on submit functionality.
But before that, let's do one thing like.
We have to remove this one log user.
And now const log out.
We are going to get that log out from the auth store.
Okay.
Similar in that case only.
And after that, there would be one button right.
So button, I guess here it would be.
Let me check out.
Okay.
So I have set up this on click event like on click equal to sorry on click functionality.
So on click equal to log out.
So now.
And also one thing like there's some error which is coming.
Okay.
So log user.
So I have removed it.
So const log user log user equal to true.
Right.
Okay.
So let's go and test this one out.
So one second.
Okay.
Log in is successful.
So we are redirecting to the homepage and let's click this log out.
So log out successful.
So this functionality is also done.
Log in and log out functionality as you can see.
So I'm going to see you in the next video.